And this should be episode number 509, I think.
然后哎嗯应该是第509期吧
I'm not sure though.
我不知道啊
This episode might be a bit disjointed.
这期可能录的断断续续的
Because SF Express will be coming by again soon.
因为这个顺丰一会还来一趟
To pick up the Wuchang rice from my place.
把我家的五常大米拿走
Because the delivery person forgot to drop it off just now.
因为刚才物流忘拿了啊
My landlord is pretty nice.
我这个房东姐姐还是不错的
And I've added a lot of new furniture to the house.
然后我给家里添了很多新的家具啊
I probably won't come back easily this time.
然后这次搬走的话就不会轻易的再回来吧
Well, not too easily, I guess.
也不是不太轻易再回来吧
But if I do come back, there will be a reason to.
回来的话还是会有理由回来的
Because I still have many friends here.
因为这边还有很多朋友什么的
And this time, a lot of people want to treat me to dinner.
嗯但是这次很多人要请我吃饭
I just won't have the time.
我就来不及了
I'm going to visit a comic convention in Shanghai on the 4th and 5th of next month.
下个月4号五号我在上海看漫展
I might arrive a week earlier.
我有可能是提前来一个星期
Or I might leave a week later.
也可能是错后走一个星期
Actually, I won’t be bringing my kids that week. That’s because I usually take care of them every week. It’s quite a hassle. Speaking of why I came to Hangzhou in the first place, as you all know, it was for shooting videos. But why leave Hangzhou now?
反而应该是那个星期不会带孩子 所以就是因为现在每星期都带孩子啊 比较麻烦 因为确实为什么一开始来杭州呢 大家也知道啊 就是为了拍视频 但是为什么现在离开杭州呢
Actually, there are many reasons.
其实呃道理有很多个
Mainly because the child is back.
主要还是因为孩子回来了
In the past, it was because of the child.
那以前是因为孩子
Didn't they go abroad directly?
这个这个这个这个这个直接不是那个出国了吗
But now the child is back in Beijing.
但是呢现在这个孩子又又回到北京了
And is preparing to go to school.
然后准备上学
So we plan to make the most of it.
所以呢我们就打算就是好好的
How should I put it?
就是怎么说呢
I'll stick to living in Beijing.
还是在北京生活吧
In any case, if I were to live as a bachelor,
总之我是觉得其实如果要是让我是单身汉的话
I would definitely choose Hangzhou.
我肯定还是选择在杭州生活
Because living in Hangzhou is indeed more convenient,
因为杭州生活确实从便利上来讲的话
it's really quite,
是非常的呃
very convenient.
具有非常大的便利性啊
Many internet companies have chosen Hangzhou as their base,
因为现在很多互联网公司都选择在杭州
and handling affairs in Hangzhou,
杭州这边办事啊
well, it's just easier.
不管怎么说
It's kind of hard to say
都是比较怎么说呢
it's more convenient
比较方便的
let me tell you
因为我跟你说
I'm in Beijing
我在北京
I feel like there are a lot of things
我感觉就是很多东西
things that are established by usage
就是他一些约定俗成的东西
that can really get on your nerves quite troublesome sometimes I am a Beijinger But I also feel that this Beijing culture is particularly something special People have their own matters
就是让你觉得很恼火 很麻烦啊 有时我是北京人 但我也感觉到这北京这种文化特别那什么 就是人有什么事情啊
If they can avoid helping you
这个能不给你办
They won't help you
就不给你办
And everyone is always hoping others will beg them for favors
然后所有的人都渗着都是希望别人来求自己啊
But in Hangzhou, that's not the case
但是在杭州没有这回事
It's all about business
因为就觉得就是生意
Business is conducted as it should be
就是生意该怎么着就怎么着啊
When it comes to business, we talk business, nothing else
在商言商无上免谈
This culture is different
就是这种文化是不一样的
which leads to
所以导致的
the city's development over thousands of years being distinct
最后这个城市几千年来的发展是不一样的啊
not quite a few thousand years
没有几千年
but if we start counting from the Song Dynasty
但从宋朝来算的话
from the Lin'an Prefecture of the Song Dynasty
从宋朝临安府来算的话
that would be a thousand years
那就是1000年
so how do we put it
所以这个东西怎么说呢
many things are established by usage
这很多事情就是约定俗成
That's it.
就是这样
Then I feel that if you're a bachelor,
然后我感觉到如果你是一个单身汉的话
coming to Hangzhou,
来到杭州啊
at least the housing prices aren't as high as in Beijing,
起码这个啊房价不是像北京那么贵
but many people say it's a food desert.
但很多人说这是美食地狱
But for me,
但是对于我来讲
a Beijinger who eats McDonald's every day,
我一个北京人天天吃麦当劳
a KFC regular,
肯德基的主
I don't really care about whether it's a food desert or not.
我也不在意什么美食地狱不地狱的啊
It’s nothing much to me.
对我来说没有什么
It’s just a bit hotter in the summer.
就是夏天会比较热一点啊
And in the winter, without heating,
冬天因为没有取暖
it can get quite cold.
会比较冷一点
But the place is blessed with talented people who are generally quite good-looking. There’s not much else to it. Unlike the harsh northern regions. But let me tell you, it all depends on whether you can adapt to it.
但是整个人杰地灵人都长得比较好看 没有什么其他的东西啊 不像在北方苦寒之地 但是我跟你说 就是看你一个人能不能适应啊
If I were to speak from my perspective
你要像在我眼里来讲的话
Shenyang would be a pretty good choice
沈阳就是一个不错的选择
But in many people's eyes
但是在很多人眼里来讲
Shenyang might not be as fancy as your hometown
可能沈阳没有你的家乡那么的fancy啊
But for me
但是对我来讲的话
whether it's the cost of living or the cultural environment
就是无论从消费程度还是这个人文环境
or the lifestyle of the people
还是说这个人的这种习惯
or the way people interact
交往的习惯
I also have a lot of friends in Shenyang
我在沈阳朋友也多
But if I had to choose myself
但是你要让我自己选的话
I would definitely travel all over the country
我肯定是全国四各地四处跑啊
spend a year in each place
一个地方住一年
But speaking of this place
但是现在这地方来讲的话
I’ve been here for three months
来了三个月
but I’ve actually stayed here for less than a month
但实际上住的时间没有一个月呢啊
mostly going back home to take care of my dad
基本上都回家照顾我爸了
and then my son came back
后来我儿子又回来了
he returned in early March
3月初就回来
So I'm here to move out for good
所以我这次来彻底搬走啊
I really do find it quite uncomfortable
觉得还是确实比较比较难受
Because the internet here
因为这边上网啊
China Telecom's network
中国电信的网
you basically don't need a booster to run Steam
基本上来讲开steam都不用开加速器啊
which is a huge advantage
这是一个非常大的一个优势啊
I want to chat with you all about
想跟大家聊聊什么呢
I just want to say to everyone
就想跟大家说
as you grow older
就随着你年龄的增长
A lot of things are constantly changing. What you used to imagine, you know, the life where you can feed yourself and not worry about others, as you get older, you might not be able to do that anymore. When you were young, you often didn't have money,
很多东西他是都是在变化的 你以前想象的这个啊 一个人吃饱全家不饿的生活 在你这个岁数上升了以后 你可能就做不到了 年轻的时候很多时候就是没钱啊
no money,
没钱
but you had plenty of time,
然后时间大把的是
and you were in good shape.
然后身体也不错
When you get to my age,
等到你到我这岁数以后
your body starts to decline gradually.
身体慢慢的就开始就不行了
You know,
你知道吗
you'll start noticing the decline.
就是你会发现就开始就不行了
I’m not kidding about this stuff.
知道我真不会拿这种事情开玩笑
I’ve found myself gradually losing stamina.
我发现自己现在渐渐的就是不行了
Maybe it’s from playing too many games on Steam.
可能就是steam上那个游戏打多了啊
The threshold keeps going up.
这个阈值咔咔往上走
And now, even watching movies is tough.
而且现在你说看片子啊
We mostly watch TS-themed movies.
都是看什么以ts为主的片子
You see, many of my friends are TS.
因为大家知道我好多朋友都是ts
I feel like my threshold has risen too quickly lately.
然后唉我觉得我现在的这个阈值上来太快了
So sometimes when I encounter a regular scene,
就导致有时候遇上一般的一点的那个场景啊
It doesn’t feel as arousing anymore.
就是感觉不是那么的唤醒了
You know what I mean?
你知道吗
To put it bluntly, it just doesn’t cut it anymore.
说白了就是不行了
From now on, you’ll be in the category of someone who goes fishing.
你以后就属于去钓鱼的这个这种范畴了
But I don’t feel as young and enthusiastic as I used to.
但是就感觉自己不像年轻的时候那么着
It's getting better and better.
越来越行了啊
I think this is a natural process of human evolution. You reach a certain age, and these defective parts gradually start to wear out. It’s a very normal process. But after they wear out, you still have several decades left to live.
这是我觉得是一种自人类的自然淘汰 你到了岁数啊 这个残次品慢慢的就开始就开始报废了 就是很正常的一个过程 但是报废了以后呢 这个还仍然有几十年可以活
So I think it’s okay.
所以我觉得还好啊
I think it’s fine.
我觉得还好
Actually, it's just that people's life goals have changed.
其实人只是人生的目标变了
Think about it, this life is actually for such things.
想一想这辈子其实为了这种事情
For women.
为了女人
In fact, most of the money spent in this life is for women.
其实这辈子花的钱主要都是为了女人
Whether it's for marriage or studying abroad.
不管是结婚啊还是留学啊
At the beginning, there was always a reason behind it.
其实最开始都是有这个有理由在里边啊
It's not like I initially wanted to study abroad.
并不是说我一开始我就想留学啊
Actually, there was a girlfriend who went to France.
其实那边有个女朋友去法国的时候
Not when she went to France.
不是去法国的时候
It was purely to learn before going to Canada
纯粹是想学去加拿大的时候
Back then, it was indeed to be with my girlfriend
那时候确实是为了跟女朋友能在一起
When you're in your twenties, you really do act strangely
20多岁时候人你也说实在也奇怪
But I always thought I wouldn't repeat the same mistake
但是你看我总认为自己不会重复的犯一个错误
Turns out I made the same mistake again in marriage
结果结婚又犯一次错误
Well, in the end, life is like that
反正呢后来就是人这一辈子
You keep making the same mistakes
总是会不停的犯一样的错误
And you don't learn from them
然后不去学习
And you don't move forward
不去进去
And it keeps repeating this process.
然后不停的会给你重复这个过程啊
Frankly speaking,
我觉得说实在的
Throughout my life, regarding this issue of temptation being a double-edged sword, I've actually experienced it quite a few times. But how can I put it, I'm not too bad myself, So when I'm doing well,
我这辈子在这个色字头上一把刀这个问题上 其实已经充分的体验过好几次了 但是呢怎么说呢 不是自己还行吗 所以自己还行的时候
I always think I can handle it,
就自己总觉得自己还可以
But wait until I really can't manage it.
但是等等到自己真不行的时候
There might be fewer distractions.
可能就没有那么多杂念了
So I think every period of time is a blessing.
所以我觉得人每一段时间都是一种福报啊
Each period is a blessing.
都是一种福报
Look at everything with a broader perspective.
把这任何事情往开了看
Thinking positively about everything is a good thing.
往开了去想都是好事啊
Don't always be gloomy.
不要总是郁郁寡欢的
Because every period has its moments.
因为每一段时间都有
Every period has its unhappy moments.
每一段时间那个不快乐的事情
If you keep dwelling on unhappy things
如果你老想着不快乐的事情
You won't truly be happy
你就不会真正快乐起来
if you focus on happy things every day
如果每天都是聚焦在快乐上的事情来讲
you might not feel so down
可能就没有那么的郁闷了
After all, life is full of the ordinary
总之啊人生在世一切东西都是常事
don't let the fear of making mistakes tie you up in knots
你也不要因为会犯错误就打不开心结
because you will make mistakes
因为会犯错误
and think your life is over
你就觉得自己那这辈子就完了
making mistakes and correcting them is a normal part of learning
犯错误再改正就是正常的一个学习环境
you won't learn without making mistakes
你不犯错
How can you change that?
你怎么能改呢
Right?
对不对
Let's talk about mending the fold after the sheep are lost. Isn't it true that we learn from our mistakes? That's how we get through it. Of course, there are certain challenges in life You might make the same mistake a few times But when you make a mistake for the first time You might not learn the lesson The second time, you learn a part of the lesson.
咱们说说亡羊补牢嘛 是不是吃一堑长一智 就是这么过来的 当然你人生中有些课题 你可能重复会犯几次错误 但你第一次犯错误的时候 你可能不吸取教训 第二次你就吸取了一部分教训
The third time, you might learn the lesson very deeply.
第三次你可能这教训你就吸取了特别深刻
It can be really painful.
特别痛苦
And that’s when the lesson truly sinks in.
你就吸取进去了
Then your mission in this life is accomplished.
那你这辈子来这投生的任务就完成了
Isn’t that right?
对不对
They say
人家说
that life is actually about learning these lessons.
其实人这一辈子就是用来教学学习这些东西
Some things just don’t make sense out of context.
有些东西不放在情境当中啊
There's no way to learn.
你就没有办法学习
So I recommend everyone to learn English.
所以我就说推荐大家学英文
When learning any language,
还学任何语言的时候呢
it's crucial to place it in context.
就是一定要放在情境当中啊
It makes sense when you put it in context.
放在情境当中就合理了
It becomes easier to learn when you place it in context.
放在情境当中就好学习了
Always put yourself in the context.
永远把自己放在情境当中
So the most convenient way is to play games.
所以最方便的方法那就是在游戏当中玩游戏啊
Because many famous titles nowadays
因为现在很多著名的大作
Like The Witcher 3 and such
比如什么巫师三啊之类的啊
Like Baldur's Gate
比如说什么博德之门啊
And so on
三之类的
Many of them are multilingual
很多东西他都是多语言的
You can use multiple languages
你都可以用多种语言
Isn't Kingdoms and Castles the same?
什么天国王朝不也是吗
Multiple languages
就是多种语言
After using multiple languages
多种语言以后
The voice acting is different
他的配音不一样
The text used is different
他的那个用的文章文字不一样
Keep repeating this process
不断的重复这个过程
Gradually, you'll learn the language
慢慢你这种语言就学会了
Just like when people watch movies Or anime You pick up a bit of Japanese You'll understand, right? So these things are a process of osmosis A process This episode is titled 'I Can't Do It'
就像大家只要是看片 看动漫 多少多少多多多少少日语的一些东西 你是会你是明白了对吧 所以说这些东西就是一种耳濡目染的一 个过程啊 这一期以我不行了为标题
To attract everyone
然后吸引大家过来
But it's okay
不过也没关系啊
When I can't do it
我不行了的时候呢
In the end, you'll find that there are new things you can do
到最后呢你会发现有些新的东西呢你又行了
Right?
对不对
So sometimes feeling capable or not
所以有的时候你觉得行与不行
Is just a matter of mindset
都是一个一念之差
When your thinking shifts and your threshold rises, many things
你的思维转变了你的这个阈值上去了很多东西
Gradually feel different
慢慢的感觉就变了
It's you who has changed
是你变了
The world hasn't changed
世界并没有变啊
I hope everyone is happy every day
希望大家呢每天都是开开心心的
And if you're not happy
然后如果要是不开心的话
Come watch my videos
就来看看我的视频